Hello everyone and welcome back to English
pod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine
and today we have a very special lesson
for everyone. It's a new level for us.
Right, it's an advanced media lesson and
we are going to be listening to an apology.
Well, it's an apology letter but we're
going to actually have someone talk it out.
Right, so what's happening
here is someone is reading a letter
they've written and they're
trying to apologize for something
and we don't really know what this something is but I
want everyone to really listen here to the words that are
being used and to the ways in which we can say sorry because
as they say there are a thousand ways to say I'm sorry.
Dear Mary, I come here today this way because
I need to apologize to you. I failed you
although I did not lie to you in words. I lied
to you with faces that did not belong to me.
I never meant to ruin the friendship
that meant the world to me.
You mean the world to me and now
I come to you asking for forgiveness.
If in your heart you find you can't
then I will understand and learn from
this experience. You came into my life
at a time when I needed you the most.
We talked about so many
things that I started to realize my
heart and my soul could actually
feel something other than heart.
You placed comfort where there was
fear, confidence when there was doubt.
A shoulder where tears could fall in
completeness where there was emptiness.
I wanted to hold on to this so badly that
I did whatever it took for you to notice.
What I didn't realize was
that I could lose my entire
being, all of who I was and
all of that I had placed in you.
I wanted to be the one who would
be there when you needed to talk.
I wanted to be the comfort for your soul
when the world was too much to handle.
I wanted to be strong for you when everything
else seemed impossible. I wanted to love you and
only the way you deserved to be loved. Never
realizing that I was destroying myself and you.
Somehow I needed you to be a
part of my life. The only problem
was that I was willing to jeopardize
everything to get that done.
All the things that I told you about how I
felt and how you make me feel were true.
Nothing else mattered to me except hearing the
laughter in your voice when you were happy.
You made my days easy to get
through in my nights peaceful.
You helped me look
forward to another day.
Even though distance separated us, just
being was enough. I'm sorry for hurting you.
And if I had to do it
all over again, I would
have been 100% with
you. Forgive me, please.
All right, we're back, so the guy seems to be
pretty sad. Yeah, this is a very intense. Well,
it's not a dialogue. It's a monologue. One person
is reading it. So it's a very intense monologue.
Very romantic. Yeah, romantic, but also an
air of melancholy. Yeah, that's true. It's
kind of like apologizing at the same time
expressing love and all these feelings.
So it was very interesting, but why don't we take a look at
a couple of phrases now in advanced media. We're not going to
analyze the entire dialogue or as we do in the other levels
actually pick out items for language takeaway or fluency builder.
So in advanced media, we're only
going to pick out a couple of words
and phrases and just talk about it
and talk about the topic in general.
Exactly. And so one of the first phrases
that we decided to talk about here is
this phrase, I failed you because this
is really the theme of the letter. Right.
So if you fail someone, it means
that you let that person down.
Okay, so you fail someone. I
failed you. We can say he failed me.
So when I really needed
that person the most that
person didn't come through
or let me down or failed me.
All right, so let's give an example maybe. I needed my
brother to pick me up because I don't have a car and
my brother was supposed to pick me up at four o'clock
and he forgot he didn't come. He really failed me.
All right, failed you. Yeah, I was
disappointed. Well, this isn't that's
not as serious as what happened here
in this in this letter, I think, right.
I think so, but we could talk about what did happen. I
think I have a theory. I know you have a theory so we can
talk about that in a minute. But before that we have
some other phrases about forgiveness and disappointment.
Right. Well, he also said
you mean the world to
me and now I come to
you asking for forgiveness.
Okay, so we've got a positive and a
negative. So the positive here is you mean
the world to me. You mean the world to
me. This means you are so important to me.
You're one of the most important people
in my life. You're worth the entire world
in my opinion. Yeah, it's a very poetic
way of saying you're very important. Yeah.
And then he says, and now I
come asking for your forgiveness.
Okay, so this implies that
he did something wrong.
I come asking for forgiveness. So
in English we ask for forgiveness.
You can also beg for
forgiveness. So please forgive me.
But you can't, you can't demand
forgiveness. I demand you for good.
No, this is the right word. All
right. What else do we have?
We've got the world again here.
He says he, the guy who's reading,
he says, you know, I wanted
to be the comfort for your soul.
So this is very, again, poetic.
When the world was too much to
handle, too much to handle is a
really important English phrase.
And I'm sure you've heard it before,
but we could talk about a little bit here.
Right. So he says when everything
else was too much to handle.
So everything was so difficult or it was
overwhelming. Right. So you could say
even in the office, man, all this work
I have to do. It's too much to handle.
Right. Right. Okay.
Too much to handle. You could
also say a child is too much to handle.
I think they said this about my brother.
He was very difficult growing up too hard.
He's too, he's too difficult to handle.
All right.
So what about in the part where he says, you place
comfort where there was fear, confidence where there was
doubt. So this structure is interesting because you
placed something where there used to be something else.
So you're placing
something, you're changing
something for something
else. It's an exchange.
So you could say you placed
comfort where there was
fear, you placed happiness
where there was sadness.
So it's always like kind of opposites, right? Exactly.
Okay. It's like where there was dark. Right. Exactly.
So that's an interesting format of saying something.
You did something where there used to be something else.
All right.
And what about this word to jeopardize?
This is a good one. I always think of the TV
game show Jeopardy, but that's a noun. This here
is a verb to jeopardize. And that means to put
something in danger or to risk losing something.
Okay. So to jeopardize your health
if you're doing something dangerous.
So smoking jeopardizes one's health.
You're putting your health at risk.
Or I don't want to jeopardize
my savings by investing everything
I have in stocks. That means I
would prefer to do something safer.
So you don't like to
jeopardize your well-being.
I like to play it safe, as I say.
All right. Very good. And last but
not least, this almost the last phrase
when he says even those distance
separated us just being wasn't enough.
What does he mean when he says just being wasn't
enough? All right. This is very romantic and tensely
romantic. He says even though we were far apart just
being so just existing, just breathing was enough.
So just knowing that she's in the
world was enough for him to feel happy.
So that's what he means
with just being wasn't enough.
Right. So being is existing.
It's being alive. Okay. Very good.
I think we should listen to this apology
letter one more time and we'll be back.
Dear Mary, I come here
today this way because
I need to apologize
to you. I failed you.
Although I did not lie
to you in words, I lied
to you with faces that
did not belong to me.
I never meant to ruin the friendship
that meant the world to me.
You mean the world to me and now
I come to you asking for forgiveness.
If in your heart you
find you can't, then I
will understand and
learn from this experience.
You came into my life at a time when I needed
you the most. We talked about so many things
that I started to realize my heart and my soul
could actually feel something other than hurt.
You placed comfort where there was
fear, confidence when there was doubt, a
shoulder where tears could fall in
completeness where there was emptiness.
I wanted to hold on to this so badly that
I did whatever it took for you to notice.
What I didn't realize was
that I could lose my entire
being, all of who I was and
all of that I had placed in you.
I wanted to be the one who would
be there when you needed to talk.
I wanted to be the comfort for your soul
when the world was too much to handle.
I wanted to be strong for you when
everything else seemed impossible.
I wanted to love you and only
the way you deserve to be loved.
Never realizing that I was
destroying myself and you.
Somehow I needed you
to be a part of my life.
The only problem was that I was willing
to jeopardize everything to get that done.
All the things that I told you about how I
felt and how you make me feel were true.
Nothing else mattered to me except
hearing the laughter in your voice when
you were happy. You made my days
easy to get through in my night's peaceful.
You helped me look
forward to another day, even
though distance separated
us just being was enough.
I'm sorry for hurting
you and if I had to do it
all over again, I would
have been 100% with you.
Forgive me, please.
All right, so what do you think he
did that he's apologizing in this way?
Because I don't think
there were a couple right
because he mentions
friendship a couple of times.
Yes, with a butt. You
don't write a letter like
this to someone who you
want to stay friends with.
You write a letter to
someone who you have some
kind of romantic or
intense feeling for, right?
So to me, this seems like a letter that
was written to someone who was a great
friend and he's afraid of losing that
because he cares even more for her.
Right, but yeah, I guess.
But do you think he
sees confessing his love
in a certain way here?
I think in some ways
he's confessing a love.
You can love your
friends. That's okay.
But more than that, he's
apologizing for something that
he thinks has completely
destroyed their friendship.
And that is where I'm very confused
because I have no idea what he did.
Well, maybe he did
something that let her down.
Maybe he became jealous of her
new boyfriend or something like that.
Yeah, or maybe it's something caddy like he
was supposed to do something with her and ended
up doing something with other people and left
her out or embarrassed her in front of people.
It's hard to say.
Have you ever written an apology letter?
Yeah, I've written a few apology letters.
I have a very strong sense of guilt.
That was raised cat like that. So in the
apology is it? Do you usually plan out
what you want to say or you just like you
just blurge your feelings onto the paper?
Well, you know me. My
personality is very planned
and organized and so
normally I have points.
So I say, if this is the
problem, there's three parts.
I have an answer for each part and
the very end I have the heartfelt apology.
Wow. It's like an essay.
I guess it's a little, yeah, it's
a little bit more organized.
If I were to write something like
this, I would just like start writing and
whatever comes out so it would
probably make less sense than your letter.
Well, I just try to stay on focused
standpoint and address the matter at hand
because otherwise then you get into other
stuff and you can make people more angry.
Right, but it is really important to write an
apology letter. Now some of the words and phrases
and the vocabulary used here can be used in
circumstances that are not only romantic, right?
You can be used in a
professional way as well, right?
That's true. In a professional sense, you
want to be careful not to get too personal.
So in a professional sense, it's good to
say that you're sorry for any mix-ups or
from misunderstandings but in the future
you'll try to make things better or improve.
But in friendships, send in families
and in romantic relationships, apology
letters are very important because
I'm a big believer in mending bridges.
A lot of people who we say
in English to burn a bridge
that means to destroy a
relationship and never go back.
But I like to mend bridges to
make sure that people who I was
friends with don't, if we have a
fight, don't just hate me forever.
Right.
That even if there's a
disagreement that they
understand my perspective
or that I understand theirs.
Yeah, that's true. I
think that's important.
What about apology emails?
Do you agree with those?
I think that they are a
necessity of the 21st century.
I mean, I live far away from
most of my friends and family and
so it's important for me to be
able to communicate in any way.
But sometimes, I mean, I'm very shy with
some people, so sometimes it's hard for me to
talk on the phone because I get stuck and
then I can't think of what I wanted to say.
And so if a letter helps in that
way to get you past your fear
or your anxiety, then by all
means and emails just as much.
I actually received a letter, a
handwritten letter through an email.
How did that happen?
They scanned the letter.
So it was still like, it still had a
very intimate and personal sense.
But obviously since the mail
takes along and everything,
they just scanned it and
then they sent it to me.
That's nice.
So I think that's a good idea.
Maybe you could try that one.
I don't agree with the one line email.
I'm sorry, forgive me.
Yeah, that's not good.
As my parents always used
to say when I was growing up
and I had to get them
fights with my little brother.
Only apologies that we accept
are the ones that are from the heart.
So I used to have to apologize
again and again until I actually meant it.
And so I think that this is a very true kind of
idea that that well, maybe not in business and work
where you have to be cordial with friends and
real relationship with people who you care about.
Obviously, real apologies
are very important.
Of course. So this is an interesting topic
and we recommend that you if you have any
other questions or doubts or maybe you want
some other explanation for this letter.
You can come to englishpot.com, leave it
in the comments section and we'll be there.
So until next time, bye!